Inventory of Alonzo J. Walter Jr. Motion Picture Film, 1938-1943
Hoover Institution Archives
Alonzo J. Walter Jr. motion picture film,
1938-1943
80023
Hoover Institution Archives
19 motion picture film reels (3.8 linear feet)
Depicts German military and aerial operations, and German political leaders during World War II.
Walter, Alonzo J., Jr.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Germany.; Moving-pictures.; World War, 1939-1945--Aerial operations.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns.; World War, 1939-1945--Germany.; World War, 1939-1945.
- Degeto Weltspiegel motion picture film: number 14 Der Rheinubergang und die Eroberung der Maginotlinie, silent 35mm film, 1940 (Reel 1)
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001019
  Scope and Contents note
  The Crossing of the Rhine River and Conquest of the Maginot Line. Label reads: 1940 (Degeto #14); Rhine and Maginot line (beginning only). 2 copies
- Reichsanstalt für Film und Bild in Wissenschaft und Unterricht (RWU) motion picture film: Fallschirmjager, silent 35mm film (Reel 2)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001035
  German paratroopers. Label reads: Paratroop training (Reichsanstalt fur Film und Bild in Wissenschaft und Unterricht [RWU]) [reel 2]
- Loss of German territory to France, 800 to 1815, silent 35mm film (Reel 3)
- Degeto Weltspiegel motion picture film: number 22 Entscheidung auf dem Balkan III. Der Sprung nach Kreta, silent 35mm film, 1941 (Reel 4)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0000988
  German invasion of Crete
- Degeto Weltspiegel motion picture film: number 5 Danzig ist weider Deutsche, silent 35mm film (Reel 5)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001038
  Danzig is German again
- Number 41 Dieppe 19 August 1942 and number 6 Im fuhrer-hauptquartier, silent 35mm film, 1939-1942 (Reel 6)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001037
  Number 41: Dieppe 19 August 1942/Number 6: In the Fuhrer's headquarters
- Alonzo J. Walter home movie compilation of uncle Daniel, ruins at Dortmund and Degeto Weltspiegel motion picture film: number 50 Heldengedenktag 1943, silent 35mm film (Reel 7)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001032
  Hero commemorative day 1943. Label reads Uncle Daniel; Ruins at Dortmund; Hitler and Goering at "Hero-Remembering Day," Munich, 1943 November [reel 7]
- FW-200 attacks on ships in the Atlantic [RWU], silent 35mm film (Reel 8)
- Reichsanstalt für Film und Bild in Wissenschaft und Unterricht (RWU) motion picture film: Die deutsche Westgrenze I, silent 35mm film, 1936 (Reel 9)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001039
  The German west boundary I, director Hans Neuberger, Berlin. Label reads German border changes, 800 to 900 [RWU] [reel 9]
- Universum Film AG (UFA) motion picture film: Eine Batterie geht in Stellung, silent 35mm film (Reel 10)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001033
  A battery goes into position. Label reads Cavalry and artillery [UFA] [reel 10]
- Degeto Weltspiegel motion picture film: number 20 Entscheidung auf dem Balkan I. Vormarsch von allen Seiten, silent 35mm film (Reel 11)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001040
  Decision on the Balkan peninsula I: advance from all sides. Label reads 1941 (Degeto #20821) [reel 11]
- Soldiers build an igloo [RWU], silent 35mm film (Reel 12)
- Degeto Weltspiegel motion picture film compilation: number 18 Die Schlacht um Frankreich; and number 19 Zwei mal Waffenstillstand, silent 35mm film, 1940 (Reel 13)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001036
  Number 18: The battle for France/Number 19: Two times armistice. Label reads Invasion of France; Hitler accepts French surrender [reel 13]
- Reichsanstalt für Film und Bild in Wissenschaft und Unterricht (RWU) motion picture film: Verkehrsflugzeug im Flughafen Berlin, silent 35mm film, 1937 (Reel 14)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0000987
  Aircraft at the Berlin airport. Label: Lufthansa at Berlin
- Osterreich kehrt heim 13 Marz 1938 and Fuhrerbesuch in Italien 3-9 Mai 1938, silent 35mm film (Reel 15)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001016
  Austria returns home 13 March 1938/the Fuhrer in Italy 3-9 May 1938
- Heimreise: die Europa auf hoher see, silent 35mm film (Reel 16)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001017
  The trip home: the Europa on the high seas. Label reads S.S. Europa at sea (Agfa)
- Universum Film AG (UFA) motion picture film: Pioniere schlagen eine brucke, silent 35mm film (Reel 17)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001041
  Soldiers are proposing a bridge. Label reads Soldiers build a pontoon bridge [UFA] [reel 17]
- Degeto Weltspiegel motion picture film compilation: number 14 Der Rheinubergang und die Eroberung der Maginotlinie; number 16 Deutsche schiffe kontrollieren die see, silent 35mm film, 1940 (Reel 18)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0002141
  number 14: The crossing of the Rhine River and conquest of the Maginot Line number 16: German ships control the sea. Label reads Breaching the Maginot Line; Advancing in France; at sea; Hitler at memorial in Munich, 1940 November 23
- Kaukasusfront: elbrusbesteigung; Fernbomber uber dem atlantischen ozean, silent 35mm film (Reel 19)
  Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001018
  The Caucasus front: Mount Elbrus; Long-range bombers over the Atlantic ocean. Label reads German mountain troops in the Caucasus; FW-200 bombers attack ships in the Atlantic [reel 19][RWU #1436]